we need to
write a while loop that takes input from
the user
performs an action and only stops when
the user types
stop so we're going to be examining the
user input here
now when we write a while loop
we need to provide a condition to this
while loop
to determine when we want it to stop
looping
as long as this condition evaluates as
true the loop will continue
so let's create a variable x that will
reference our user input
while x is not equal to
stop then we want to continue looping
let's begin just by outputting a message
to the user
and let's run our code
we've gotten an error undefined local
variable or method
x this is on line one
so let's go back and look at our code
on line one we use x as part of our
condition but we haven't yet defined it
so let's go ahead and define x on line
one outside of this
loop and we can just set it equal to an
empty string right now
now let's run our code again and see if
it runs without error
this time we don't get an error however
we have an infinite loop
[Music]
and that's because we don't ever
reassign x x continues to reference an
empty string so the condition x is not
equal to stop
just continually evaluates as true and
our while loop continues looping
so let's add a little bit more code to
our while loop
we'll collect an answer from the user in
response to our question how are you
feeling
then we'll display another message to
the user
do you want me to ask you again and
their response to this question
will determine whether or not we
continue looping
so here is where we'll reassign x
we'll use git s to collect the user
input
and chain a method call to chomp to
remove the newline character
now when we enter stop we expect that
ruby will
break out of this loop let's run our
code again
so we're prompted how are you feeling
well input good
and the program asks us do you want me
to ask you again
let's input yes and we loop again we're
asked how we're feeling again
this time i'll input stop and you can
see that the loop continues
that's because in our program we're
specifically looking for
stop with all uppercase characters
our user input was in lowercase
characters
so this time i'll enter stop with all
capital letters
and we expect to break out of the loop
and we do